Guide to the Fales Manuscript Collection circa 1700-2000 MSS.001
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Letter sized boxes
  - Morison, Samuel Eliot (1887-1976), undated (Box 124, Folder 15)
  - Morley, Christopher (1890-1957): Correspondence [see also Box 125.5], undated (Box 124, Folder 16)
  - Morley, Christopher (1890-1957): MS. [see also Box 125.5], undated (Box 124, Folder 17)
  - Morley, Henry, undated (Box 124, Folder 18a)
  - Morley, John, undated (Box 124, Folder 18b)
  - Morris, Charles, undated (Box 124, Folder 19a)
  - Morris, George Pope (1802-1864), undated (Box 124, Folder 19b)
  - Morris, Jane (Burden) ("Mrs. William Morris"), undated (Box 124, Folder 20a)
  - Morris, Lewis, Sir (1833-1907), undated (Box 124, Folder 20b)
  - Morris, May (Wm's daughter) (1862-1938): Correspondence, undated (Box 124, Folder 21)
  - Morris, May (Wm's daughter) (1862-1938): Drawings, undated (Box 124, Folder 22)
  - Morris, May (Wm's daughter) (1862-1938): Photocopies of Correspondence [see also Legal & Oversize], undated (Box 124, Folder 23)
  - Morris, May (Wm's daughter) (1862-1938): Miscellaneous flyers from scrapbook; Kate Whitaker's passport, undated (Box 124, Folder 24)
  - Morris, May (Wm's daughter) (1862-1938): Photographs of M.M. and of Kate Whitaker, undated (Box 124, Folder 25)
  - Morris, William (1834-1896), undated (Box 124, Folder 26)
  - Morris, William (1834-1896): MS. Grattir the Strong; May, May, undated (Box 124, Folder 27)
  - Morris, Wright (1910- ), undated (Box 124, Folder 28a)
  - Morrison, Arthur (1863-1945), undated (Box 124, Folder 28b)
  - Morse, Samuel F. B. [see also Legal Size for printed Mat.], undated (Box 124, Folder 29)
  - Morshead, J. F., undated (Box 124, Folder 30a)
  - Mortimer, J., undated (Box 124, Folder 30b)
  - Morton, David, undated (Box 124, Folder 30c)
  - Morton, John Madison (1811-1891), undated (Box 124, Folder 30)
  - Mosenthal [from Arthur Machan proofs], undated (Box 124, Folder 31a)
  - Moses, Robert, undated (Box 124, Folder 31b)
  - [Moss, Howard: see Box 126], undated (Box not specified, Folder data_value_missing_d66712e5dc023268b25684017cf27c23)
  - Motherwell, William (1797-1835), undated (Box 124, Folder 32a)
  - Motley, John Lothrop (1814-1877), undated (Box 124, Folder 32b)
  - Motley, Willard (1912- ) MS. Let No Man Write My Epitaph; 2 A.L.s., undated (Box 124, Folder 33)
  - Mottl, Felix, undated (Box 124, Folder 34a)
  - Mottram, R. H. (1883- ), undated (Box 124, Folder 34b)
  - Moore, George (1852-1933): Correspondence (1), undated (Box 125, Folder 1)
  - Moore, George (1852-1933): Correspondence (2), undated (Box 125, Folder 2)
  - Moore, George (1852-1933): Correspondence (3), undated (Box 125, Folder 3)
  - Moore, George (1852-1933): Correspondence and MS. (5) [sic], undated (Box 125, Folder 4)
  - Morley, Christopher (1890-1957): MS., undated (Box 125.5, Folder data_value_missing_65ef0df38a0965077f19ba11846bf66d)
  - Moss, Howard (1922-1987): MSS., undated (Box 126, Folder 1)
  - Moss, Howard (1922-1987): Addresses, etc. [2 books], undated (Box 126, Folder 2)
  - Moss, Howard (1922-1987): Notebook A [1963] (Box 126, Folder 3)
  - Moss, Howard (1922-1987): Notebook B [1966] (Box 126, Folder 4)
  - Moss, Howard (1922-1987): Notebook C [1969] (Box 126, Folder 5)
  - Moss, Howard (1922-1987): Notebook D [undated] (Box 126, Folder 6)
  - Moss, Howard (1922-1987): Notebook E - F [undated] (Box 126, Folder 7)
  - Moss, Howard (1922-1987): Notebook G - I [undated] (Box 126, Folder 8)
  - Moss, Howard (1922-1987): Notebook 1 [1964] (Box 126, Folder 9)
  - Moss, Howard (1922-1987): Notebook 2 [1973?], ca. 1973 (Box 126, Folder 10)
  - Moss, Howard (1922-1987): Notebook 3 [1977?], ca. 1977 (Box 126, Folder 11)
  - Moulton, Hugh Fletcher (1876- ): MSS. As the Coroner Saw It; The Employment Bureau; The Experiment of Mr. Winston; Hall-Marked, undated (Box 127, Folder 1)
  - Moulton, Hugh Fletcher (1876- ): MSS. The Man Who Loved His Wife; The Opportunist, undated (Box 127, Folder 2)
  - Moulton, Hugh Fletcher (1876- ): MSS. A St. Andrew's Cross; Scraps of Paper; A War Time Holiday, undated (Box 127, Folder 3)
  - Moulton, Hugh Fletcher (1876- ): MS. Untitled (1) [pp. 33-118][see Legal Folders for pp. 1-32], undated (Box 127, Folder 4)
  - Moulton, Hugh Fletcher (1876- ): MS. Untitled (2) [pp. 119-205], undated (Box 127, Folder 5)
  - Moulton, Hugh Fletcher (1876- ): MS. Untitled (3) [pp. 206-298], undated (Box 127, Folder 6)
  - Moulton, Hugh Fletcher (1876- ): MS. Untitled (4) [unpaged], undated (Box 127, Folder 7)
  - Moulton, Hugh Fletcher (1876- ): MS. Untitled (5) [unpaged], undated (Box 127, Folder 8)
  - Moulton, Hugh Fletcher (1876- ): MS. Untitled (6) [unpaged], undated (Box 127, Folder 9)
  - Moulton, Hugh Fletcher (1876- ): MSS.: Miscellaneous Untitled; 1) A tall, loose-limbed, blue-eyed man; 2) Helen Smithson snapped to...; 3) I'm going to write a book, undated (Box 127, Folder 10)
  - Moulton, Hugh Fletcher (1876- ): MSS.: Miscellaneous Untitled; 4) "It's a good word" Bungalow, undated (Box 127, Folder 11)
  - Moulton, Hugh Fletcher (1876- ): MSS.: Miscellaneous Untitled; 5) Charley evidently didn't like Murchison, undated (Box 127, Folder 12)
  - Moulton, Hugh Fletcher (1876- ): MSS.: Miscellaneous Untitled; 6) I slept solid until two o'clock, undated (Box 127, Folder 13)
  - Moulton, Hugh Fletcher (1876- ): Miscellaneous Fragments, undated (Box 127, Folder 14)
  - Moulton, Louise Chandler (1835-1908), undated (Box 127, Folder 15)
  - Muck, Karl, undated (Box 128, Folder 1a)
  - Mudie, Charles Edward (1818-1890), undated (Box 128, Folder 1b)
  - Mu¨ller, F. Max (Friedrich Max) (1823-1900), undated (Box 128, Folder 1c)
  - Muhlenberg, William Augustus (1796-1877), undated (Box 128, Folder 2a)
  - Muir, Edwin (1887- ): Review of Graham Greene, End of the Affair, undated (Box 128, Folder 2b)
  - Mumford, Lewis, undated (Box 128, Folder 3)
  - Munro, Neil (1864-1930), undated (Box 128, Folder 4a)
  - Munroe, Kirk (1850-1930), undated (Box 128, Folder 4b)
  - [Murchison, see Box 128.A], 1690-2000 (Box not specified, Folder data_value_missing_16730c2a24f24df84808ec37ef2cd544)
  - Murdoch, Iris, undated (Box 128, Folder 5)
  - Murdoch, James E., undated (Box 128, Folder 6)
  - Murfree, Mary Noailles (1850-1922), undated (Box 128, Folder 7a)
  - Murphy, Emma W., undated (Box 128, Folder 7b)
  - Murray, David Christie, undated (Box 128, Folder 7c)
  - Murray, Gilbert (1866- ), undated (Box 128, Folder 7)
  - Murray, John (1778-1843), undated (Box 128, Folder 8)
  - Murray, Judith Sargent Stevens (1751-1820), undated (Box 128, Folder 9a)
  - Murray, Lindley (b. 1790), undated (Box 128, Folder 9b)
  - Murray, Margaret Alice, undated (Box 128, Folder 9c)
  - Myers, Eveline, undated (Box 128, Folder 10a)
  - Myers, William Starr (1877-1956), undated (Box 128, Folder 10b)
  - Murchison, Lady: Souvenirs of Lady Murchison, Extra-illustrated Letterbook in Purple Crushed Morocco with Gold Tooling, undated (Box 128.5, Folder 1)
  - Nassau Ferry, undated (Box 129, Folder 1a)
  - Nast, Thomas, undated (Box 129, Folder 1b)
  - Nathan, George Jean, undated (Box 129, Folder 1c)
  - Nathan, Robert, undated (Box 129, Folder 2)
  - Navarro, Mary (Anderson) de, Mme (1859-1940), undated (Box 129, Folder 3)
  - Neal, John (1793-1876), undated (Box 129, Folder 4a)
  - Neihardt, John Gneisenau (1881- ), undated (Box 129, Folder 4b)
  - Nelson, Alec: MS. Judith Shakespeare, undated (Box 129, Folder 5)
  - Nemerov, Howard: T.S. Sleeping Beauty, undated (Box 129, Folder 6)
  - Nemerov, Howard: Correspondence, 1986-1989 (Box 129, Folder 6a)
  - Newberry, John Strong: [1911?], ca. 1911 (Box 129, Folder 7a)
  - Newbolt, Henry John, Sir (1862-1938), undated (Box 129, Folder 7b)
  - Newell, Robert Henry (1836-1901), undated (Box 129, Folder 8a)
  - Newman, Frances (d. 1928), undated (Box 129, Folder 8b)
  - Newman, John Henry, Cardinal (1801-1890), undated (Box 129, Folder 8c)
  - Newton, Alfred Edward (1863-1940), undated (Box 129, Folder 9)
  - Newton, Richard Heber (1840-1914), undated (Box 129, Folder 10a)
  - Nicholls, Arthur Bell (1817-1906), undated (Box 129, Folder 10b)
  - Nichols, Beverley (1899- ), undated (Box 129, Folder 11a)
  - Nichols, George Herbert F., undated (Box 129, Folder 11b)
  - Nichols, John Gough (1806-1873), undated (Box 129, Folder 12a)
  - Nichols, Robert Malise Bowyer (1893-1944), undated (Box 129, Folder 12b)
  - Nicholson, Meredith (1866- ), undated (Box 129, Folder 13a)
  - Nicholson, William (1872-1949), undated (Box 129, Folder 13b)
  - Nightingale, Florence (1820-1910), undated (Box 129, Folder 14a)
  - Niles, Hezekiah (1777-1839), undated (Box 129, Folder 14b)
  - Nock, Albert J. (1873-1945), undated (Box 129, Folder 14c)
  - Noel, Conrad (1869-1942), undated (Box 129, Folder 15a)
  - Noel, Thomas (1799-1861), undated (Box 129, Folder 15b)
  - Norman, Charles: MS., undated (Box 129, Folder 16)
  - Norris, George W., undated (Box 129, Folder 17)
  - Norris, Kathleen (1880- ): Correspondence, undated (Box 129, Folder 18)
  - Norris, Kathleen (1880- ): MS., undated (Box 129, Folder 19)
  - Norris, William Edward (1847-1925), undated (Box 129, Folder 20)
  - Norse, Harold: [1963] (Box 129, Folder 21)
  - Norse, Harold: to Ira Cohen [1964-1965] (Box 129, Folder 22)
  - Norse, Harold: to Ira Cohen [1966-1970] (Box 129, Folder 23)
  - Norse, Harold: to Ira Cohen [1963?-1970], ca. 1963-1970 (Box 129, Folder 24)
  - Norse, Harold: MS., undated (Box 129, Folder 25)
  - Norse, Harold: Photographs by Ira Cohen, undated (Box 129, Folder 26)
  - Northampton, Spencer Joshua Alwyne Compton, Marquis (1790-1851), undated (Box 129, Folder 27)
  - Norton, Caroline (Sheridan) (1808-1877): Correspondence, undated (Box 129, Folder 28)
  - Norton, Caroline (Sheridan) (1808-1877): MS., undated (Box 129, Folder 29)
  - Norton, Charles Eliot (1827-1908), undated (Box 129, Folder 30)
  - Noyes, Alfred (1880- ), undated (Box 129, Folder 31)
  - [Nuttall, Jeff: see Box 130], 1690-2000 (Box not specified, Folder data_value_missing_66c200f4b1a884b864ea3e6afe87a12d)
  - Nye, Edgar Wilson ("Bill Nye") (1850-1896), undated (Box 129, Folder 32)
  - Nuttall, Jeff: MS. Bomb Culture [pp. 1-155] [see also Legal Size], undated (Box 130, Folder 1)
  - Nuttall, Jeff: MS. Bomb Culture [pp. 156-240], undated (Box 130, Folder 2)
  - Nuttall, Jeff: MS. The Boy with the Face of Sour Apples, undated (Box 130, Folder 3)
  - Nuttall, Jeff: MS. The Boy with the Face of Sour Apples [notes] [see Legal Size for 1st drafts], undated (Box 130, Folder 4)
  - Nuttall, Jeff: MS. The Case of Isabel [finished TS.], undated (Box 130, Folder 5)
  - Nuttall, Jeff: MS. The Case of Isabel, undated (Box 130, Folder 6)
  - Nuttall, Jeff: MS. The Case of Isabel [notes], undated (Box 130, Folder 7)
  - Nuttall, Jeff: MS. Love Play, undated (Box 130, Folder 8)
  - Nuttall, Jeff: MS. Mr. Watkins Got Drunk, undated (Box 130, Folder 9)
  - Nuttall, Jeff: MS. Mr. Watkins Got Drunk [notes], undated (Box 130, Folder 10)
  - Nuttall, Jeff: Notebooks, undated (Box 130, Folder 11)
  - Nuttall, Jeff: Pictorial [7 drawings] [see also Legal Size for 2 drawings], undated (Box 130, Folder 12)
  - Oakes, James, undated (Box 131, Folder 1a)
  - Obenchain, L. C., undated (Box 131, Folder 1b)
  - O'Brien, Sophie (Raffalovich), undated (Box 131, Folder 1c)
  - [O'Casey, Sean: see Box 132], 1690-2000 (Box not specified, Folder data_value_missing_98cabe8013c3cac8ccd7730c6129c8e8)
  - [O'Connell, Jerry: see Box 133], 1690-2000 (Box not specified, Folder data_value_missing_4f2a753475db5538c7cf8b472291351f)
  - O'Connor, Flannery, undated (Box 131, Folder 2)
  - Odets, Clifford (1906- ), undated (Box 131, Folder 3)
  - O'Donnell, Peadar, undated (Box 131, Folder 4a)
  - O'Faolain, Sean, undated (Box 131, Folder 4b)
  - O'Flaherty, Liam (1897- ), undated (Box 131, Folder 5)
  - O'Flaherty, Liam (1897- ): MS. The House of Gold, undated (Box 131, Folder 6)
  - Ogilvy, Virginia, Mrs., undated (Box 131, Folder 7)
  - O'Hara, Frank: MS. The General's Return, 1962 (Box 131, Folder 8)
  - O'Keeffe, Adelaide (1776-1855), undated (Box 131, Folder 9)
  - Olds, Sharon, undated (Box 131, Folder 10)
  - Oliphant, Margaret (1828-1897), undated (Box 131, Folder 11)
  - Oliphant, Margaret (1828-1897): MS., undated (Box 131, Folder 12)
  - Oliver, George (Oliver Onions, pseud.), undated (Box 131, Folder 13a)
  - Olivier, Edith, undated (Box 131, Folder 13b)
  - Ollivant, Alfred, undated (Box 131, Folder 13c)
  - Ollivier, E´mile (1825-1913), undated (Box 131, Folder 13)
  - [O'Neill, Eugene: see Box 134], 1690-2000 (Box not specified, Folder data_value_missing_edbca32a55b3e852f19a83bdacf4bc92)
  - O'Neill, Rose, undated (Box 131, Folder 14)
  - [Onions, Oliver: see Oliver, George, Box 131], 1690-2000 (Box not specified, Folder data_value_missing_dcf84d74f2d7301aa789afbfecec1371)
  - Opie, Amelia Alderson (1769-1853): Correspondence [1803-1829] (Box 131, Folder 15)
  - Opie, Amelia Alderson (1769-1853): Correspondence [1830-1839] (Box 131, Folder 16)
  - Opie, Amelia Alderson (1769-1853): Correspondence [1840-1849] (Box 131, Folder 17)
  - Opie, Amelia Alderson (1769-1853): Correspondence [1850- ], 1850's (Box 131, Folder 18)
  - Opie, Amelia Alderson (1769-1853): MS. and Miscellaneous, undated (Box 131, Folder 19)
  - Oppenheim, E. Phillips (1866-1946), undated (Box 131, Folder 20)
  - Oppenheim, James (1882-1932), undated (Box 131, Folder 21a)
  - Orcutt, William Dana (1870- ), undated (Box 131, Folder 21b)
  - [Orczy, Emmuska Orczy, Baroness (1865-1947): Boxes 135 & 135.5], 1690-2000 (Box not specified, Folder data_value_missing_59eda45e9ace83d9186951b7f3a9cd68)
  - O'Reilly, John Boyle (1844-1890), undated (Box 131, Folder 22a)
  - O'Reilly, Mary Boyle (1873- ), undated (Box 131, Folder 22b)
  - [O'Rell, Max: see Blone¨t, Paul, Box 19], 1690-2000 (Box not specified, Folder data_value_missing_00c33c540e348850a077757e86ca22c3)
  - O'Riordan, Conal O'Connell (1874-1948), undated (Box 131, Folder 22c)
  - Orlovsky, Peter A., undated (Box 131, Folder 23a)
  - Orr, Christine (1899- ), undated (Box 131, Folder 23b)
  - Orr, Christine (1899- ): MS. Poems, undated (Box 131, Folder 24)
  - Orsay, Alfred Guillaume Gabriel, comte d' (1801-1852), undated (Box 131, Folder 25)
  - Osborne, Lloyd (1868-1947): Correspondence, undated (Box 131, Folder 26)
  - Osborne, Lloyd (1868-1947): MS., undated (Box 131, Folder 27)
  - Osborne, Lloyd (1868-1947): Pictorial, undated (Box 131, Folder 28)
  - O'Shaughessy, Edith Louise (Coves) (d.1939), undated (Box 131, Folder 29a)
  - O'Sullivan, Vincent (1872-1940), undated (Box 131, Folder 29b)
  - O'Sullivan, Se´amas: 1-3: 2) [removed from The earth-lover: and other essays]; 3) [removed from Twenty-five Lyrics], undated (Box 131, Folder 29c)
  - Otis, Harrison Grey (1765-1848), undated (Box 131, Folder 29)
  - [Ouida: see De la Rame´e, Box 39 & Oversize Box 1], 1690-2000 (Box not specified, Folder data_value_missing_33da30d147a4a0078ffe9bea15a1d3c6)
  - Oursler, Fulton, undated (Box 131, Folder 30a)
  - Oursler, Grace (Perkins), undated (Box 131, Folder 30b)
  - Ovington, Earle, undated (Box 131, Folder 30c)
  - Owen, Robert, undated (Box 131, Folder 30)
  - Owen, R. Dale, undated (Box 131, Folder 30e)
  - Owen, Will (1869- ) [see also Legal Size for Drawing]; Oxenham, John, undated (Box 131, Folder 31)
  - Oxford, Bishop of: [1854?], ca. 1854 (Box 131, Folder 32)
  - Ozick, Cynthia: MS. Washington Square, 1946 [from NYU/English Newsletter], undated (Box 131, Folder 33)
  - O'Casey, Sean (1880-1964): Correspondence, undated (Box 132, Folder 1)
  - O'Casey, Sean (1880-1964): Correspondence to Carney, Jack [1933-1940] (Box 132, Folder 2)
  - O'Casey, Sean (1880-1964): Correspondence to Carney, Jack [1941] (Box 132, Folder 3)
  - O'Casey, Sean (1880-1964): Correspondence to Carney, Jack [1942] (Box 132, Folder 4)
  - O'Casey, Sean (1880-1964): Correspondence to Carney, Jack [1943] (Box 132, Folder 5)
  - O'Casey, Sean (1880-1964): Correspondence to Carney, Jack [1944] (Box 132, Folder 6)
  - O'Casey, Sean (1880-1964): Correspondence to Carney, Jack [1945] (Box 132, Folder 7)
  - O'Casey, Sean (1880-1964): Correspondence to Carney, Jack [1946] (Box 132, Folder 8)
  - O'Casey, Sean (1880-1964): Correspondence to Carney, Jack [1947] (Box 132, Folder 9)
  - O'Casey, Sean (1880-1964): Correspondence to Carney, Jack [1948; undated] (Box 132, Folder 10)
  - O'Casey, Sean (1880-1964): Correspondence to Carney, Mina [1941-1948] (Box 132, Folder 11)
  - O'Casey, Sean (1880-1964): Envelope, undated (Box 132, Folder 12)
  - O'Casey, Sean (1880-1964): Pictorial, undated (Box 132, Folder 13)
  - O'Connell, Jerry: Correspondence: A - B, undated (Box 133, Folder 1)
  - O'Connell, Jerry: Correspondence: C, undated (Box 133, Folder 2)
  - O'Connell, Jerry: Correspondence: E, undated (Box 133, Folder 3)
  - O'Connell, Jerry: Correspondence: F, undated (Box 133, Folder 4)
  - O'Connell, Jerry: Correspondence: H, undated (Box 133, Folder 5)
  - O'Connell, Jerry: Correspondence: K, undated (Box 133, Folder 6)
  - O'Connell, Jerry: Correspondence: Yurka, Blanche, undated (Box 133, Folder 7)
  - O'Neill, Eugene (1888-1953): Correspondence to J.O. Lief, undated (Box 134, Folder 1)
  - O'Neill, Eugene (1888-1953), undated (Box 134, Folder 2)
  - O'Neill, Eugene (1888-1953), undated (Box 134, Folder 3)
  - O'Neill, Eugene (1888-1953): Alexander, Doris, The Tempering of E.O., undated (Box 134, Folder 4)
  - O'Neill, Eugene (1888-1953), undated (Box 134, Folder 5)
  - O'Neill, Eugene (1888-1953), undated (Box 134, Folder 6)
  - O'Neill, Eugene (1888-1953): Photographs, undated (Box 134, Folder 7)
  - Orczy, Emmuska Orczy, Baroness (1865-1947): Correspondence [1903-1933] (Box 135, Folder 1)
  - Orczy, Emmuska Orczy, Baroness (1865-1947): Correspondence to Hilda Neal [1918-1945] (Box 135, Folder 2)
  - Orczy, Emmuska Orczy, Baroness (1865-1947): MS. The First Sir Percy [last chapter]; Miscellaneous, undated (Box 135, Folder 3)
  - Orczy, Emmuska Orczy, Baroness (1865-1947): MS. No Greater Love [pp.1-152], undated (Box 135, Folder 4)
  - Orczy, Emmuska Orczy, Baroness (1865-1947): MS. No Greater Love [pp. 153-349], undated (Box 135.5, Folder 5)
  - Orczy, Emmuska Orczy, Baroness (1865-1947): Scrapbook, The Scarlet Pimpernel, undated (Box 135.5, Folder 6)
  - Paderewski, undated (Box 136, Folder 1a)
  - Page, Thomas Nelson (1853-1922), undated (Box 136, Folder 1b)
  - Page, Walter Hine (1855-1918), undated (Box 136, Folder 2a)
  - Paget, Clarence A. E., undated (Box 136, Folder 2b)
  - Paget, Francis, undated (Box 136, Folder 2c)
  - Paget, James, Sir (1814-1899), undated (Box 136, Folder 2)
  - Paget, Violet (1856-1935), undated (Box 136, Folder 3)
  - Pailleron, Edouard (1834-1899), undated (Box 136, Folder 4a)
  - Pailthorpe, Frederick W., undated (Box 136, Folder 4b)
  - Pain, Barry Eric Odell (1864-1928), undated (Box 136, Folder 5)
  - Paine, Albert Bigelow (1861-1937), undated (Box 136, Folder 6)
  - Palgrove, Francis, Sir (1788-1861), undated (Box 136, Folder 7a)
  - Palgrove, Francis Turner (1824-1897), undated (Box 136, Folder 7b)
  - Palmer, Edward Henry (1840-1882), undated (Box 136, Folder 8a)
  - Palmer, Ray (1808-1887), undated (Box 136, Folder 8b)
  - Palmerston, Henry John Temple (1784-1865), undated (Box 136, Folder 8c)
  - Pardee, Julia (1806-1862), undated (Box 136, Folder 9)
  - Parker, Dorothy: Galley and TS., undated (Box 136, Folder 10)
  - Parker, Gilbert, Sir (1862-1932): 1886-1898 (Box 136, Folder 11)
  - Parker, Gilbert, Sir (1862-1932): 1900-1910 (Box 136, Folder 12)
  - Parker, Gilbert, Sir (1862-1932): 1911-1916 (Box 136, Folder 13)
  - Parker, Gilbert, Sir (1862-1932): 1920- (Box 136, Folder 14)
  - Parker, Gilbert, Sir (1862-1932): undated (Box 136, Folder 15)
  - Parker, Gilbert, Sir (1862-1932): Correspondence to Fridenberg, Percy, undated (Box 136, Folder 16)
  - Parker, Gilbert, Sir (1862-1932): Correspondence to Stoddart, Joseph Marshall, undated (Box 136, Folder 17)
  - Parker, Joseph (1830-1902), undated (Box 136, Folder 18a)
  - Parker, Theodore (1810-1860), undated (Box 136, Folder 18b)
  - Parkman, Francis (1829-1893), undated (Box 136, Folder 19a)
  - Parrish, Anne (1888- ), undated (Box 136, Folder 19b)
  - Parrish, Maxfield, undated (Box 136, Folder 19c)
  - Parry, William E., Sir (1790-1855), undated (Box 136, Folder 19)
  - Parsons, Alfred, undated (Box 136, Folder 19e)
  - Parton, James (1822-1891): [ca. 1860's; 1882; 1885] (Box 136, Folder 20)
  - Partridge, Bernard, Sir (1861-1945), undated (Box 136, Folder 21a)
  - Pascal, Ernest (1896- ), undated (Box 136, Folder 21b)
  - Pascar, Henriette, undated (Box 136, Folder 21c)
  - Pashley, John: Notebook (Math), undated (Box 136, Folder 22)
  - Pasternack, Boris, undated (Box 136, Folder 23)
  - Pater, Walter Horatio (1839-1894), undated (Box 136, Folder 24a)
  - Patchen, Kenneth, undated (Box 136, Folder 24b)
  - Paterson, A. J. B., undated (Box 136, Folder 25a)
  - Patmore, Coventry (1823-1896), undated (Box 136, Folder 25b)
  - Paton, Alan (1903- ), undated (Box 136, Folder 26a)
  - Paton, (Joseph) Noel, Sir (1821-1901), undated (Box 136, Folder 26b)
  - Paul, Charles Kegan (1828-1902), undated (Box 136, Folder 26c)
  - Paulding, James Kirke (1778-1860), undated (Box 136, Folder 27a)
  - Pawling, Sydney P. (of Heineman), undated (Box 136, Folder 27b)
  - Paxton, J., undated (Box 136, Folder 28a)
  - Paxton, Joseph, undated (Box 136, Folder 28b)
  - Payen-Payne, James Bertrand de Vincheles (1866- ), undated (Box 136, Folder 28c)
  - Payn, James (1830-1898), undated (Box 136, Folder 29)
  - Payne, J. B., undated (Box 136, Folder 30a)
  - Payne, John (1842-1916), undated (Box 136, Folder 30b)
  - Payne, John Howard (1791-1852), undated (Box 136, Folder 31)
  - Peabody, Andrew Preston (1811-1893) & Josephine, undated (Box 137, Folder 1)
  - Peake, Richard Brinsley (1792-1847); Pearson, Edwin; Peel, Robert, Sir (1788-1850), undated (Box 137, Folder 2)
  - Pemberton, Max, Sir (1863-1950): 1893-1898 (Box 137, Folder 3)
  - Pemberton, Max, Sir (1863-1950): 1899-1902 (Box 137, Folder 4)
  - Pemberton, Max, Sir (1863-1950): 1911-1913 (Box 137, Folder 5)
  - Pemberton, Max, Sir (1863-1950): 1914-1927; undated (Box 137, Folder 6)
  - Pemberton, Thomas Edgar (1849-1905); Pendexter, Hugh (1875- ); Percival, James Gates (1795-1856), undated (Box 137, Folder 7)
  - Pepperrell, William, Sir (1696-1759), undated (Box 137, Folder 8)
  - Perry, Bliss (1860-1954), undated (Box 137, Folder 9)
  - Perugini, Chatherine Macready (Dickens) (1839-1929); Peterkin, Julia, undated (Box 137, Folder 10)
  - Petersen, Olaf Finn; Peterson, Charles Jacobs (1819-1887), undated (Box 137, Folder 11)
  - Petersen, Will: to Samperi, Frank, undated (Box 137, Folder 12)
  - Petrova, Olga (1886- ); Pettie, John (1839-1893); Phelps, William Lyon (1865-1943); Philipoy, Ren´, undated (Box 137, Folder 13)
  - Phillips, David Graham (1867-1911); Phillips, Florence; Phillips, Henry W. (1869-1930); Phillips, Jayne Anne, undated (Box 137, Folder 14)
  - Phillips, Samuel; Phillips, Stephen (1868-1915); Phillips, Ulrich Bonnell (1877-1934); Phillips, Watts (1825-1874), undated (Box 137, Folder 15)
  - Phillips, Wendell (1811-1884), undated (Box 137, Folder 16)
  - Phillpotts, Eden (1862-1960): Correspondence [1895-1910] (Box 137, Folder 17)
  - Phillpotts, Eden (1862-1960): Correspondence [1911-1919] (Box 137, Folder 18)
  - Phillpotts, Eden (1862-1960): Correspondence [1920-1922] (Box 137, Folder 19)
  - Phillpotts, Eden (1862-1960): Correspondence [1925-1929] (Box 137, Folder 20)
  - Phillpotts, Eden (1862-1960): Correspondence [1930-1948; undated] (Box 137, Folder 21)
  - Phillpotts, Eden (1862-1960): Correspondence to Colles, 1894-1920 (Box 137, Folder 22)
  - Phillpotts, Eden (1862-1960): Correspondence to Mr. Savage, undated (Box 137, Folder 23)
  - Phillpotts, Eden (1862-1960): Miscellaneous, undated (Box 137, Folder 24)